*****************************

THE COMBAT COLLECTION
music for violent video games
by
JOHN LEONARD FRENCH

*****************************

IMPORTANT - for best results with this guide, disable text wrapping or use the combat collection .pdf file, available with your download or at www.johnleonardfrench.com

*****************************The complete Combat Collection comprises orchestral epics, ethnic rhythms and iconic themes for games with violence and action at their core. Specially created for game developers, the collection features full tracks and seamless loops all designed for combat, action and adventure games.High quality audio. Each track is provided as a CD quality 16bit, 44.1khz, uncompressed .wav file that’s ready for import, normalised to preserve bit depth and professionally mastered to provide the very best sound.Gapless loops. Looped tracks have been created to cycle perfectly, in exact sync, with correct reverb tails and at the precise signal zero crossing point. Meaning no pops, silences, clicks, sudden changes or other unwanted noises, just great music.Fascinating instruments. The combat collection uses some wonderfully rare and unique instruments such as the hang drum, Darabuka and lapsteel however it really wouldn’t be a combat collection without an anvil, would it now?Feedback and suggestions for future packs are welcome.Enjoy,John Leonard French support  |  feedback  |  commissions  |  requests
www.johnleonardfrench.com  info@johnleonardfrench.com @johnlfrench
© 2013

*****************************

Track List
Track				Description						Key	Tempo	T-Sig*	Time	Size	Starter	PRO
Ambience 1 Ethnic Full		Ethnic drums with melodic hang drum			-	90 bpm	4/4	2:03	21.6 mb		yesAmbience 1 Ethnic Loop		Seamless loop without hang drum				-	90 bpm	4/4	1:25	15.1 mb		yesAmbience 2 Ethnic Full		Middle eastern marketplace				A min	85 bpm	3/4	1:41 	17.9 mb		yesAmbience 3 Wasteland Full	Distant violin and piano in an arid wasteland		C min	75 bpm	3/4	1:14	13.1		yesAmbience 4 Loop			Seamless percussion loop with string bed		C	120 bpm	4/4	0:48	8.5 mb		yesAmbience 4 Layers		x3 Layer parts for dynamic crossfading			C	120 bpm	4/4	-	-		yesBig Battle 1 Full		Frantic orchestral epic					D min	130 bpm	4/4	1.39	17.6 mb		yesBig Battle 1 Loop**		Seamless loop						D min	130 bpm	4/4	1:32	16.3 mb		yesBig Battle 2 Full		Large scale battle with orchestral stabs		D min	170 bpm	3/4	1:41 	17.9 mb	yes	yesBig Battle 2 Loop**		Seamless loop						D min	170 bpm	3/4	1:39	17.6 mb		yesBig Battle 3 Full		Gritty battle piece with ripped brass			D min	90 bpm	4/4	2:33	26.8 mb		yesBig Battle 4 Full		Pounding timpani and distorted brass			C min	110 bpm	3/4	1:26	15.2 mb		yesBig Battle 4 Loop**		Seamless loop						C min	110 bpm	3/4	1:12	12.7 mb		yesClose Combat 1 Loop		Hand to hand, one on one percussion			-	190 bpm	3/4	1:04	11.4 mb	yes	yesClose Combat 2 Loop		Circle of death! Simple, duelling percussion loop	-	160 bpm	3/4	0:36	6.4 mb		yesEspionage 1 Loop 1		Full instrumentation					B	70 bpm	4/4	0:54	9.7 mb	yes	yesEspionage 1 Loop 2		Simple instrumentation					B	70 bpm	4/4	0:27	4.8 mb		yesEspionage 2 Loop		Mysterious pedal bass piece with sound design		D	60 bpm	4/4	1:04	11.3		yesEspionage 3 Loop		Drum loop with a dark synth bed and bass pedal		E min	140 bpm	4/4	1:29	15.7 mb		yesMain Theme 1			‘The Combat Collection’ title theme			A min	105 bpm	3/4	2:56	31.1 mb	yes	yesMain Theme 2			‘Brothers in arms’ tragic theme				D	70 bpm	4/4	1:15	13.3 mb		yesMain Theme 3			‘Phoenix Rising’ building piano theme			A min	130 bpm	3/4	1:50	19.4 mb		yesPursuit 1 Full			Controlled continuos chase music with a manic vibe	D min	80 bpm	4/4 	1:36	17.1 mb	yes	yesPursuit 1 Loop**		Seamless loop without intro				D min	80 bpm	4/4	1:24	14.8 mb		yesPursuit 2 Full			Chaotic chase music with mad percussion			C min	190 bpm	4/4	0:54	9.6 mb		yesPursuit 2 Loop**		Seamless loop						C min	190 bpm	4/4	0:50	8.9 mb		yesDefeats				x3 Short themes for deaths or serious moments		-	-	-	-	-		yesVictories			x3 Short themes for victories and level ups		-	-	-	-	-		yesHorror scare long		Scratching violins with build up			-	-	-	0:22	3.9 mb		yesHorror scare short		Without build up					-	-	-	0:11	2 mb		yesQuest SFX - bongos		x6 Waypoint / objective sounds				-	-	-	-	-		yesQuest SFX - snares		x5 Waypoint / objective sounds				-	-	-	-	-		yesBONUS TRACKS			x3 Bonus tracks, Ambient cave / Main theme / Battle	-	-	-	-	-		yes
* Time signature** Includes start / end parts
KeyFULL: 		A complete piece of music with a start and finish.SIMPLE:	Variation of a full piece with reduced or simpler instrumentation and style.LOOP: 		Can be looped seamlessly to form a longer piece of music.START:		A starting segment for use with looped music. Add after before a looped file startsEND:		An ending segment for use with looped music. Add after a looped file finishes. 		(May also be suitable as a victory / level up cue)LONG/SHORT:	Indicating longer and edited versions of the same piece when available.

*****************************Using loopsThe looped files in the collection include the reverb tail at the end of the piece and are looped in exact sync at the zero crossing point. This means the looping section will be seamless. To further enhance looped files, selected tracks include ‘START’ and ‘END’ files to bookend the looped file, creating a longer looping track that still has a start and end section. When importing music as .mp3, looping is not usually recommended unless gapless mp3 looping is available. This is because the compression process may sometimes remove samples creating a gap.Technical informationFile type: 		.wav - waveform audio - PCM uncompressedChannels:		2 - stereoStereo pan law:		Equal power (no attenuation for centre pan)Bit depth:		16 bit (dithered from 24 bit)Bit rate:		1,411,200Sample rate:		44.1 KhzNormalised:		yes, to -1dbIMPORTANT: all of the music recordings contained within this pack are protected under contract and may be used only for the purposes and within the conditions contained in the END USER LICENCE AGREEMENT. Copyright remains with the author at all times and tracks are provided for synchronisation within projects via non exclusive licence. No music from this pack, either full or in part may be sub-licenced, sold or provided for use to a third party, played publicly or sampled to create a new musical product. Crediting the authorBy using this music in your project, there is no obligation to credit the author however should you wish to do so then please observe the following. Credit is kindly appreciated.Name:	 	John Leonard FrenchCredit:		‘Music courtesy of’, ‘Music provided by’ etc.IMDB:		http://www.imdb.com/name/nm3623682/Support / tutorialsinfo@johnleonardfrench.com www.johnleonardfrench.com 

*****************************